**WEBSITE** https://github.com/viboud12 **MOBILE** +1 (919) 903 - 7212 **EMAIL** viboud@live.unc.edu LinkedIn

https://goo.gl/3pjXpR

As a cell biology graduate student and conference developer, I am committed to advancing research through my own work in the lab, as well as by contributing to the growth and value of the scientific

community by fostering collaborations and fruitful interactions.

## EXPERIENCE

**VINCENT BOUDREAU** 

RESEARCH FACILITATOR **Physiology Course** Marine Biological Laboratory Woods Hole, MA Summer 2016/2017

CO-ORGANIZER & **CO-FOUNDER** The Triangle Cytoskeleton Meeting 2014-2017

CITY COORDINATOR Research Triangle Park Pint of Science US

2016

**GRADUATE STUDENT** Biology **UNC-Chapel Hill** Chapel Hill, NC 2013-Present

VISITING STUDENT **Biophysics** UC, Berkeley Berkeley, CA Spring 2016

**STUDENT Physiology Course** Marine Biological Laboratory Woods Hole, MA Summer 2015

**GRADUATE STUDENT Biochemistry** University of Montreal Montreal, OC 2012-2013

Under Dr. Wallace Marshall's supervision, I developed a research plan and oversaw the success of the Physiology Course's students in answering biological questions in a discovery-based setting. We examined the cell biological and metabolic relationship between a wild species of the pond dwelling protist Stentor and its endosymbiotic alga.

Through the Triangle Cytoskeleton Meeting, our team aims to provide a forum to present and discuss cutting edge research on the cytoskeleton in addition to promoting communication and collaboration between research institutions. Our 2014 and 2015 meetings gathered over 200 people and raised more than \$30K in grants and sponsorships.

Through a series of discussions about the importance, the similarities, the dierences and the processes of doing art and science, we are striving to bridge the communication gap between the general public and highly skilled artists and scientists.

## EDUCATION

Under Dr. Paul Maddox's supervision, I study the cell biological requirements and the timing of the last events that govern how cells divide using cultured human cells, flies and worms as model organisms and genetic, cell biological, imaging and computational as technological approaches.

Established a collaboration with Dr. Hernan Garcia's lab to study the timing and regulation of transcription activation with respect to cell division using advanced microscopy, image analysis and computational biology approaches.

I completed this research-based, intensive bootcamp-like course aimed at bridging the biological, physical and computational sciences to lead to new research discoveries. During the course I discovered a new structure within a pond-dwelling organism that physically supports the life of the organism's endosymbiotic algae.

Under the supervision of Dr. Vincent Archambault, I conducted genetic and proteomic screens to identify novel molecular interactions of critical importance to the exit from mitosis using the fly embryo. (Transfered to UNC).

FUNDING

DOCTORAL FELLOWSHIP

2014-2017

Fonds de recherche en santé du Québec (FRSQ) - Quebec's NIH Competitive funding: 25% success rate

POST COURSE RESEARCH

FELLOWSHIP - 2016

Funding to conduct research in Dr. Hernan Garcia's laboratory at the University of California - Berkeley

PHYSIOLOGY COURSE Summer 2015

Burroughs Wellcome Fund and Caswell Grave Scholarship Fund

MASTER'S FELLOWSHIP

2012-2014

Fonds de recherche en santé du Québec (FRSQ) - Quebec's NIH

Competitive funding: 33.8% success rate

RESEARCH FELLOWSHIP

2012-2014

Faculté des études supérieurs et postdoctorales (FESP) Support for the direct transition to the PhD from the BSc

**UNDERGRADUATE FELLOWSHIP** 

2010

The Canadian Society for Mucopolysaccharide and Related Diseases

PRIZES

**IMMIGRANT TRAVEL AWARD** 

2015

Travel award to attend the American Society for Cell Biology's 2015 annual meeting in San Diego, CA

Geston & Schatz, P.C.

**OUTSTANDING POSTER** PRESENTATION - 2015

Developmental & Stem Cell Biology Symposium University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

**BEST ORAL PRESENTATION** 2013

Simon-Pierre Noël prize - Biochemistry department University of Montreal

**BEST POSTER PRESENTATION** 

2012

GE Healthcare prize

4th IRIC Scientific Day, University of Montreal

**BEST POSTER PRESENTATION** Second place

2012

Canadian Society for Molecular Biosciences (CSMB) Biochemistry department, University of Montreal

**PRESENTATIONS** 

TALK

**Kinetochore Dynamics** Meeting - Copenhagen, DK 2015

......

Completing mitosis requires the timely reactivation of nucleocytoplasmic trafficking

**INVITED SPEAKER** 

University of Sherbrooke

2014

PP2A interagit génétiquement et physiquement avec le centromère

Biochemistry department symposium

TALK University of Montreal

2013

Dissecting the roles of Protein Phosphatase 2A in mitotic exit Biochemistry department symposium

TALK **MCCCM** 2012

PP2A-B55/Tws collaborates with CENP-C for the cell cycle progression and regulates merotelic kinetochore-microtubule attachments in anaphase

Montreal Cell Cycle and Cytoskeleton Meeting

LANGUAGES

**ENGLISH FRENCH RUSSIAN**